EDWARD S. LE

(714) 603-5555

edwardsle.github.io

le_edward@yahoo.com

linkedin.com/in/edwardsle

• Garden Grove, CA

SUMMARY

Graduated from the University of California, Irvine with a Bachelor of Computer Science degree in Artificial Intelligence. Also a freelance website developer with 6 years of experience in building websites for small companies. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for web projects.

EDUCATION

- 2020: University of California, Irvine B.S. in Computer Science
- 2017: Orange Coast College A.S. in Computer Programming

EXPERTISE

- UX & UI design
- Coding & Programming
- Web development

- Multimedia design
- Multi-tasking

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C, C++, Java, Python, JavaScript, PHP, HTML, CSS, SQL, XML, x86 Assembly, Shell Scripting

FRAMEWORKS AND TOOLS

Laravel, NodeJS, Pytorch, Photoshop, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, After Effects

Experience working with YouTubers, editing social media videos.

CMS

WordPress, Magento, OpenCart, Joomla

EXPERIENCE

2018 - now	Web-developer at BolsaGroup
o F	d full-stack websites using: ront-end: HTML, CSS, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap ack-end: Laravel, Core PHP, Java, MySQL, JSON, XML d front-end with back-end frameworks and services such as October CMS and Shopify
2018 - now	Technician at VietskyTV
	ork including recording and editing events: operating the lights for video productions, cameras, recording live events.

2016 - 2018	Delivery driver Domino's Pizza in Orange.	
 Responsible for prompt delivery of orders. Average delivery time was 7.64 minutes per order. 		
2014 - 2016	Salesman at T-Mobile retailers in Santa Ana	
 Maintain knowledge of current promotions and policies regarding payments and exchanges, and privacy practices. Took care of 50+ customers every month, and opened 220+ new accounts. Awarded "Employee of the Month" honor on multiple occasions. 		
2014	Web developer at LSW in Westminster	
 Involved in Full Life Cycle of Software Development Life-Cycle (SDLC) preparing Requirement Specification documents, design documents, Test cases and Analysis, User Training documents and Technical Help documents. 		
2010 - 2013	Web developer at WORLD Corp. in Vietnam.	
 3 years of strong experience in front-end designing. Created 100+ templates selling on ThemeForest. Joined the core team of the company and developed successful 100+ web pages. 		

PROJECTS IN DATA SCIENCE & STATISTICS

	<u> </u>	
3/2019 -6/2019	Image Denoising Using Deep Neural Network	
 Source code: https://github.com/edwardsle/imagedenoise.git Designed and implemented a Deep Neural Network to denoise images using Python and Google Cloud Virtual Machine Accomplished 8.34% overall improvement in denoised photos compared to 11.14% of state-of-the-art BM3D method 		
1/2019 - 3/2019	Genetic Algorithm in OpenAI Gym	
 Source code: https://github.com/edwardsle/Genetic-Algorithm.git Optimized and evaluated an algorithm to train an animated actor in simulation using Python in Ubuntu Achieved a 20% better score compared to a published result from UC Berkeley 		
3/2018 - 5/2018	Search Engine	
 Source code: https://github.com/edwardsle/Search-Engine.git Created an inverted index of a given 37,500 HTML files corpus and imported it to MySQL Implemented a search engine using TF-IDF ranking, Java EE Designed a web interface for the search engine using Bootstrap, Vue, JSON 		

PROJECTS IN WEB DEVELOPING

INOJEC	JIJIIN VVLDI	DEVELOPING	
2019		The Aura - an online beauty school	
•			
2019		CL Constructions - construction services	
•			
2018			
•	http://www.a52usatrading.com/		
2018		Fabflix - E-commerce Web Application on AWS	
•	 A website function similar to Netflix (browsing, searching, and purchasing movies from a remote server). Implemented on AWS using a variety of Java, Javascript, servlets, HTML, Apache Tomcat, AJAX, CSS files, and XML files to create the website while also being linked to a MySQL database. Increased scalability and security by implementing recapcha, cookies, and load balancing via master-slave instances. 		
2018		NhaDatUSA	
•	•	nhadatusa.com/ Laravel, MySQL	
2018		Mimi's Nails Spa	
•		isnails.com/ Laravel, MySQL	
2017		Khoi Hanh Magazine	
•		chikhoihanh.com Laravel, MySQL	
2017		55Moving	
•	http://55m Bootstrap,	oving.com/ Laravel, MySQL	
2014		LSWCMS	
•	http://wo-t	own.com/lswcms/	

- The owner needed a system to manage his three phone-repair shops
- The system manages employees, inventory, and daily income.
- Daily report; Inventory report; Employee timesheet;
- Implemented on GoDaddy using pure PHP and JavaScript linked to a MySQL database.